Prepare for glory!
300 is a action, adventure, war film directed by Zack Snyder.
Based on Frank Miller's graphic novel, "300" is very loosely based the 480 B.C.
Battle of Thermopylae, where the King of Sparta led his army against the advancing Persians; the battle is said to have
inspired all of Greece to band together against the Persians, and helped usher in the world's first democracy.
King Leonidas, played by Gerard Butler.
Gorgo, played by Lena Headey.
Theron, played by Dominic West.
Dilios, played by David Wenham.
Captain, played by Vincent Regan.
Stelios, played by Michael Fassbender.
300 is a 2006 American epic historical action film directed by Zack Snyder,
who co-wrote the screenplay with Kurt Johnstad and Michael B.
It is based on the 1998 Dark Horse comic book limited series of
the same name by Frank Miller and Lynn Varley.
The film, like its source material, is a fictionalized retelling of
the Battle of Thermopylae in the Greco-Persian Wars.
The plot revolves around King Leonidas (Gerard Butler), who leads 300 Spartans into battle against the
Persian "God-King" Xerxes (Rodrigo Santoro) and his invading army of more than 300,000 soldiers.
As the battle rages, Queen Gorgo (Lena Headey) attempts to
rally support in Sparta for her husband.
The film also features Michael Fassbender in his film debut.
The story is framed by a voice-over narrative by the
Spartan soldier Dilios (David Wenham).
As an unreliable narrator, Dillos introduces various historical inaccuracies and other
fantastical elements, placing 300 within the genre of historical fantasy.
300 was filmed mostly with a superimposition chroma key technique
to replicate the imagery of the original comics.
An unfinished cut of 300 premiered at the Austin
Butt-Numb-A-Thon on December 9, 2006.
The completed film then premiered at the Berlin International Film Festival on February 14, 2007, before being released
in both conventional and IMAX screens in the United States on March 9, and on home media on July 31.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its visuals and style but received criticism from historians, who
criticized its historical inaccuracies, most notably its depiction of the Persians, which some characterized as Persophobic.
Grossing over $468.8 million, the film's opening was the 24th-largest in box office
history at the time, and became the tenth highest-grossing film of 2007.
The film earned a leading ten nominations at the 34th Saturn Awards, winning two for
Best Action, Adventure, or Thriller Film and Best Director (for Snyder).
A sequel, titled Rise of an Empire, based on Miller's previously unpublished
graphic novel prequel Xerxes, was released on March 7, 2014.
The film explores themes of army, narration, grave, gore, based on true story.